<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>mrtn.me</title><link>http://mrtn.me/</link><description>mrtn.me</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>antoine@mrtn.me (Antoine Martin)</managingEditor><webMaster>antoine@mrtn.me (Antoine Martin)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mrtn.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Debugging a failing OpenStack image</title><link>http://mrtn.me/posts/2023/01/13/debugging-a-failing-openstack-image/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Antoine Martin</author><guid>http://mrtn.me/posts/2023/01/13/debugging-a-failing-openstack-image/</guid><description>The problem On my alpine-openstack-vm project, There is a CI process producing a VM image for OpenStack. The process involves testing that the machine boots. The test fails, but the machine is actually booted. What doesn’t work is the ssh access. As the machine can only be reached via SSH with a private key for obvious security reasons, not having access prevents proper debug.
The objective The objective is to be able to run the produced VM locally to assess the issue.</description></item><item><title>Multiple Docker environments on Windows</title><link>http://mrtn.me/posts/2022/05/11/multiple-docker-environments-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Antoine Martin</author><guid>http://mrtn.me/posts/2022/05/11/multiple-docker-environments-on-windows/</guid><description>On Windows and docker platforms, your docker enviornment tends to get messy as time goes by.
You can start over from a clean sheet with docker system prune --all but sometimes you would like to keep some images around. This post shows how to set up multiple docker environments on Windows with the help of WSL2 (Windows Subsystem For Linux) and Alpine.
How it works The idea is to run docker on WSL and use a docker alias on the windows side to invoke the docker command in the WSL distribution.</description></item><item><title>Useful Python packages discovery sites</title><link>http://mrtn.me/posts/2022/05/02/useful-python-packages-discovery-sites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Antoine Martin</author><guid>http://mrtn.me/posts/2022/05/02/useful-python-packages-discovery-sites/</guid><description>Python is an awesome language with an awesome ecosystem. It is both mature and very active. You are rarely left alone when you need to be doing something new. There are always one or more open source libraries or framework to help you achieve your goal.
But now you&amp;rsquo;re left with a dilemma: Which one to choose ?
The criteria are fairly simple. You want a library actively used and maintained, with the biggest community possible.</description></item><item><title>Checking Google Play Signatures on .Net</title><link>http://mrtn.me/posts/2012/11/15/checking-google-play-signatures-on-net/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Antoine Martin</author><guid>http://mrtn.me/posts/2012/11/15/checking-google-play-signatures-on-net/</guid><description>With In-App Billing on Android, each time a purchase occurs, your application receives a JSON payload containing information about the purchase, as well as its signature with your developer certificate.
Google encourages you to verify that the signature is valid to authentify the purchase. You can do that inside the application, but if the delivery of the purchase involves a server, it is better to do it on the server to prevent client code manipulation.</description></item><item><title>Mirror a Git Repository Through Ssh</title><link>http://mrtn.me/posts/2012/11/15/mirror-a-git-repository-through-ssh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Antoine Martin</author><guid>http://mrtn.me/posts/2012/11/15/mirror-a-git-repository-through-ssh/</guid><description>Redmine can show the timeline of a Git repository but this repository needs to be local (see here). When you host your repository externally (on GitHub, for instance), you need to synchronize your remote repository on your Redmine server.
The following shell script is an All in one command that can be easily put in the crontab to mirror the repository on your Redmine server :
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 #!</description></item><item><title>Avoid Thread Issues While Testing an Android Service</title><link>http://mrtn.me/posts/2012/11/08/avoid-thread-issues-while-testing-an-android-service/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Antoine Martin</author><guid>http://mrtn.me/posts/2012/11/08/avoid-thread-issues-while-testing-an-android-service/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>The
<a href="http://developer.android.com/tools/testing/testing_android.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Android Test Framework</a>
provides many tools to test parts of an Android application, and the
<a href="http://developer.android.com/reference/android/test/ServiceTestCase.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">ServiceTestCase</a>
in particular to test your
<a href="http://developer.android.com/reference/android/app/Service.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Service</a>
classes.</p>
<p>This class is quite useful but you may find yourself scratching your head
because your test does not work like it should. This happens in particular if
you&rsquo;re doing some background work in your service, relying for example on
<a href="http://developer.android.com/reference/android/os/AsyncTask.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">AsyncTask</a>
for it.</p>
<p>Read on if you want to understand why it doesn&rsquo;t work and find a solution for
it.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Unlock and Root a Nexus Device</title><link>http://mrtn.me/posts/2012/10/25/unlock-and-root-a-nexus-device/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Antoine Martin</author><guid>http://mrtn.me/posts/2012/10/25/unlock-and-root-a-nexus-device/</guid><description>Having an unlocked and rooted device provides several advantages :
Easy backup and restore with Nandroid backup, Easy firmware replacement and updates installation, Advanced debugging capabilities. The following instructions allow unlocking and rooting a Nexus device (Galaxy Nexus, Nexus 7) from the command line on a Linux machine. It involves:
Backuping your device, Unlocking the bootloader, Restoring the backup, Rooting the device. Prerequisites Here is the list of prerequisites :</description></item><item><title>Quickly Deploy a Git Project on a Server With Ssh</title><link>http://mrtn.me/posts/2012/10/24/quickly-deploy-a-git-project-on-a-server-with-ssh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Antoine Martin</author><guid>http://mrtn.me/posts/2012/10/24/quickly-deploy-a-git-project-on-a-server-with-ssh/</guid><description>So you have this brand new project my_project of yours with your local Git repository set up and you want to quickly make it available for others to clone on your repository server.
All your projects are located in your server git.mycompany.com under /srv/git. You&amp;rsquo;re using the user named git to connect to your server with the SSH private key located in ~/.ssh/git.
Here is the quickiest way to deploy your projet:</description></item><item><title>Installing Redmine on Centos 6 Dot 2 Wiht Mysql and Apache</title><link>http://mrtn.me/posts/2012/07/06/installing-redmine-on-centos-6-dot-2-wiht-mysql-and-apache/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Antoine Martin</author><guid>http://mrtn.me/posts/2012/07/06/installing-redmine-on-centos-6-dot-2-wiht-mysql-and-apache/</guid><description>I needed recently to install the excellent project management tool Redmine on a CentOS 6.2 machine. There are some tutorials on the Web (here or here) but they are a little bit outdated. The following is a method that works as of today.
Pre-requisites Logged as root, install the following packages:
1 yum install make gcc gcc-c++ zlib-devel ruby-devel rubygems ruby-libs apr-devel apr-util-devel httpd-devel mysql-devel mysql-server automake autoconf ImageMagick ImageMagick-devel curl-devel And then install the bundle ruby gem:</description></item><item><title>Django on Windows: Run Celery as a Windows Service</title><link>http://mrtn.me/posts/2012/07/04/django-on-windows-run-celery-as-a-windows-service/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Antoine Martin</author><guid>http://mrtn.me/posts/2012/07/04/django-on-windows-run-celery-as-a-windows-service/</guid><description>In my previous post, I showed how to set up a Django project on a Windows Server to be served behind IIS. After setting up the server, the next thing we want with a Django application is to be able to run background and scheduled tasks, and Celery is the perfect tool for that.
On Windows, background processes are mostly run as Windows Services. Fortunately, Python for Windows Extensions (a.k.a pywin32) provides facilities to create a Windows Service.</description></item></channel></rss>